How many have ordered
DVDs and haven't paid?
Claire. Uh, yeah.
I could stop by on my way
to school. It's really important.
Um... Uh, Cheryl,
can I call you back?
Okay. Great. Bye.
Yes, Phil. What?
I was going through your drawer in
the bathroom looking for some lip stuff...
'cause my... Lips were dry.
God, you know me. Phil.
Remember the spa certificates we
got at the children's hospital auction?
Mm-hmm. Well, look at
this. They expire tomorrow.
Oh, well, what are you gonna do?
Claire, I don't think you're grasping
the magnitude of this package...
valued at over $250.
- Sweetie...
- If you don't use 'em,
then all our money
just goes to charity.
What am I supposed to do? Somewhere
between dropping off Alex at orchestra...
and picking up
Luke from practice...
Oh, and burning a bunch
of DVDs of the talent show...
I'm gonna, what, pop
in for a quick salt scrub?
I thought Cheryl
was doing the DVDs.
She's supposed to, but
somehow she's got me doing it.
Here's what you do. You
say, "Cheryl, no can do today.
Need a little me time."
Have you met Cheryl?
That'll be my new nickname. I'll be Claire
"Me Time" Dunphy. It's not worth the headache.
Just say you're sick. Then I'll run
into her and it'll be a whole thing.
If that happens, say you were
on your way to the pharmacy.
Phil, darling, no. Not helping.
Fine. I'll give them to
Florence Gunderman at work.
Her hands are gross ever
since she took up the banjo.
Hey, Mom, I need some money
for lunch. We're all gonna go...
Oh, my God! Take off my
sweater! Mom, tell her to take it off!
Alex, take it off.
Last week she wore my sweatshirt
without asking. That is true.
Oh, please, that was an honor
for your stupid old sweatshirt.
It was the first time the
top half got any exercise.
Now, Mom, that's my
favorite sweater. I just got it.
You know what you girls need to
learn to do? You need to learn to share.
Because that's what sisters do.
All right, Haley, nothing's
gonna happen to your sweater.
Right, Alex? Hmm?
Okay, fine.
Then I will just go put on
your favorite nerdy T-shirt,
the one with the guy from
Back to the Future on it.
That's Albert Einstein.
And it is not nerdy.
Well...
Hi.
- Hey, Daddy. How was
the farmer's market?
- Well, it was great.
- But guess what
the new spinach is.
- Um, radicchio?
- Kale.
- No!
I know. I was just as
blown away as you are.
Oh! Well, I guess we're
going to have to adopt... yay...
A new attitude towards kale.
Maybe we'll even
adopt... a new vinaigrette.
Adopt. Yay!
Okay, what's going on here?
I'm taking the negative charge
out of the word "adopted." Yay.
What did Oprah do now?
She had a girl on who at 16
found out that she was adopted,
and felt betrayed and ran
away and became a stripper,
and not the heart-of-gold
kind, the by-the-airport kind.
Okay.
All right, go get your
gavel, Judge Judy.
No, not at all. I'm
adopting... Ah...
A tolerant attitude toward
your flights of lunacy.
Adopting! Yay!
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ Hey ♪♪
Alex, come on. Hurry up. The later
we are, the more Cheryl texts me to do.
I'm coming. I'm coming.
Tell me again why the violin
just wasn't you. It's too happy.
Oh, my God. Okay, hang on.
Hang on. Hang on. Let's see.
It might not be a big deal.
Here we go. Let's see. Oh! Okay.
Is it bad? No,
it's gonna be fine.
You're gonna be okay.
Oh, honey.
Hey, I forgot my phone. Hi.
What? Nothing. I love you.
So weird. You better not spill
anything on that. Okay, dork?
Relax. Half the 11th grade's
been inside this sweater.
More than anything,
I want my girls to stop
fighting and be close.
I want them to share clothes and do
each other's hair and gossip about boys,
like I used to do with Mitchell.
Gloria, let's go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Hey, Jay, have you
noticed a spring in my step?
Oh, kids say cruel things. That
doesn't mean you'll turn out that way.
No. We have something in
common. I'm seeing a younger woman.
- How much younger
are we talking about?
- Thirteen months.
Her name's Chloe.
- She makes me feel
like a fifth grader again.
- Good for you, kid.
Mmm. There they are...
My two dirty old men.
Hey, pretty soon you're
gonna be north of 40,
and I'm gonna have to trade
you in for a newer model.
Am I right, buddy?
That's my mother, Jay.
You ready?
It's such a beautiful day.
Why do we have to do this?
Because when this thing is behind
us, we never have to think about it again.
Come on.
I went to a funeral
last Saturday,
and it got me thinking about where Gloria
and I were gonna end up after we die.
Yeah, it's been a fun week. I don't
like loose ends. So I made a few calls.
I found these people selling a couple of
primo plots in the best cemetery in town.
Not that I'm gonna
go there anytime soon.
Don't be so sure.
With all that
bacon that he eats.
Well, I gotta give my
cholesterol pills something to do.
Mmm. Mmm. I don't care
how much they promote it.
Kale is a garnish. It's not
ready to anchor a meal.
Look at this. Oh, my God!
Lily's little hat that we bought
her at the airport in Vietnam.
Remember how cute she looked?
Remember how I used to wear it...
and walk around and act like
I had a giant head? Mm-hmm.
That was good acting. Oh!
What are you doing? I'm putting together
a scrapbook of how Lily became ours.
Her adoption certificates and
pictures of her from her village,
all out in the open, so she
has nothing to be ashamed of.
You leaving that on all day? And
I'm also gonna write a little storybook,
something I can read her at bedtime...
called "Two Monkeys and a Panda."
Oh. She's the panda
because she's Asian.
And we're monkeys
because... I can draw monkeys.
Okay. Well, I think
this is a great project,
and I believe you
are gonna finish it.
Oh, my God! What?
Lily's adoption certificate.
Her name is Lily
Tucker Pritchett. Right.
Not Tucker-hyphen-Pritchett
like it's supposed to be.
First name, Lily. Middle name,
Tucker. Last name, Pritchett.
Well, that can't be right.
This is a legal document.
She only has your last name.
My name's just a middle name.
Stay calm. Don't get upset. Nobody
knows anyone's middle name.
Quick. What's my
middle name? Scott.
Of course you know mine. We're a
couple. This is obviously a mistake.
But you're the one who
filled out this paperwork.
You don't make mistakes like
this. You correct mistakes like this.
You did this on purpose.
What?
You buried my name so your
name could have top billing.
No, I am not gonna sit here and listen to
you accuse me of something so horrible.
It makes so much sense now...
why you wanted to fill
out all these legal forms.
Well, I'm a lawyer. I fill
out all the legal forms...
ever since you signed up for
a 12-year gym membership.
The more you spend,
the more you save.
All the women at work were
too busy to use the certificates.
So I called the spa and asked
them to extend the expiration date.
But they said no. Really?
Here's something
they didn't count on:
You mess with Phil
Dunphy, the claws come out.
You have very nice
hands. Soft like lady's.
Thank you, Kim.
I appreciate that.
My wife never seems to notice.
This is it. Ta-da!
What is "ta-da"?
I'm just saying
this is it. Ta-da.
"Ta-da" is when you do a flip,
or where the magician
cuts the pretty lady in half,
not when you show someone where
you want to shove their dead body.
I'm not gonna argue the
proper use of "ta-da." This is it.
Seriously? In the file cabinet?
It's called a crypt. And how are
you not getting how great this is?
We're four down
from Bugsy Siegel.
No. I'm not going into any
wall. I'm going in the ground.
Sorry. Not me. There's enough not to like
about death without adding dirt and worms.
The whole thing
gives me the willies.
You die, you go to the ground.
It's natural. You
go back to the earth.
Here you're just a
mushy bag of bones...
rotting away for all eternity.
Sorry for your loss.
Can we get the hell out of here?
What am I supposed
to tell the guy?
Tell them we don't want our bodies inside
these drawers where God cannot find us.
These are not like our drawers at
home. People can find things in these.
I'm thinking of getting bangs.
Ooh, you totally should. You
would be so cute with bangs.
You have the
face for it. I don't.
Oh, there's my better
half. Kim, would you mind?
Thank you. You're welcome.
- Hey, honey, where are you?
- Oh, I'm on my way to Downey.
Oh. Did you know Karen and
Richard Carpenter grew up in Downey?
What a random and
not helpful fact, Phil.
I'm sorry. I'm having
kind of a rough day.
Yeah, I'm kind of having
a rough day myself.
Look, Phil, I need you to
take care of dinner for me.
What's wrong? Alex ripped
Haley's favorite sweater,
and now I'm driving
around from store to store...
trying to find the exact same
one before Haley finds out.
Don't do that. Just explain
to her what happened.
- Uh-uh. Haley's not
gonna understand.
- Sure, she will.
No, Phil, you don't understand.
I'm trying to avoid this
turning into a whole big thing.
Then just get her something close.
She'll never know the difference.
Phil, could you just take care of
dinner, sweetie? That's all I'm asking.
I'm just saying there's
a simpler way to do this.
There is no simpler way.
Just make dinner. Thank you.
Hello?
What?
Mr. Pritchett!
We're the Rutledges,
the ones selling the spots.
Hi. Hi.
Oh, my gosh. Look, honey.
I hadn't heard.
Martin is in.
Well, look at that. I'm sorry.
Is that a friend of yours?
We've made a point to get to
know everyone in the neighborhood.
We think it makes it less
awkward, you know, later.
Oh, I'm sorry. This
is my wife, Gloria.
Oh.
I'm Ed, and this is my bunk.
And this is my loving wife and
devoted mother of three, Winnie.
She'll be here. Well, I don't
know what our lineup is yet.
But at home I sleep on the
right side, so probably there.
We don't mean to be rude, but you seem
to be much younger than your husband.
You're not rude. I'm very much
younger. Is that a problem?
Well, it's just that
there's a good chance...
you'll be moving in
long before she would.
Our concern is,
your wife remarries,
and she wants to be laid to
rest with her new husband.
So she sells this spot
to the highest bidder.
And we're left lying next
to a complete stranger...
without even so much as
a formal "how do you do?"
Gloria, tell them you're in.
I don't know, Jay.
I think they have
a very good point.
And they're not crazy at all.
What do you mean
they have a good point?
I don't think this
is going to work.
Good luck getting
someone into your drawers.
It occurs to me that I may
have gotten a little too upset...
and jumped to some conclusions
that were perhaps not true.
I realize now...
that you would never intentionally
do something so unthinkable, so...
I just wanted to say I'm
sorry for accusing you.
- I did it.
- I knew it. You two-faced...
- Let me explain.
- There... There is no explanation.
There is just no excuse.
I just wanna know why.
Okay. You know how some women
say they forget how painful childbirth was?
Well, I-I think that you were forgetting
how panicked you were before we got Lily.
- You were freaking out.
- I was not.
So it says that we can put the
mattress at one of three different levels.
Which one should
we do? I don't know.
Well, just think about how
far down she should be...
I don't know. I can't do this!
Okay. Oh, this
latch system's great.
What did people do before this? I
don't know. Stop asking me questions.
Cam... I can't do this. I can't.
Well, I... I don't see what
that has to do with anything.
I was scared that it was just
gonna all be too much for you...
and that you were gonna leave,
and then I would be the
one taking care of a baby,
and half of her last name would
belong to the guy who left us.
It was a mistake. I'm sorry.
I wanted to have it changed,
but I needed to get your signature,
and I was afraid that it would start a
big fight and that you would hate me...
Okay, I'm confused. You're saying
that if she tells me she has a problem,
I'm not supposed to help her?
Not unless she asks for your help.
But if she lets me help her, I
can make her problem go away.
Oh! That is such
a male thing to say.
Well, forgive me
for being a man. Mm.
Mango or kiwi? Ooh, kiwi.
When you say,
"Do this or do that,"
all she's hearing is,
"I'm smarter than you."
Believe me, she
doesn't think that. Mm.
She doesn't want you
to solve her problems.
She just wants you
to give her support...
so that she can solve
her problems herself.
Yes, and sometimes... sometimes
she just wants a sympathetic ear.
Whoa. Whoa. Oh, yes. Mm-hmm.
Maybe it's all the creams, but
that just made sense, girlfriends.
Okay, yeah. So if Claire says,
"I hate getting
stuck in traffic,"
I shouldn't say, "Maybe
you should leave earlier."
No. Or, "Don't get
on the freeway."
I should just say, "I
know. It's so frustrating."
Yes, that's it. Really? Yes!
And if she says, "The waiter
I had today was so rude,"
I shouldn't say, "Maybe you
should have just ordered...
something on the
menu for once." No.
I should just say,
"What a jerk."
Yes! Yes!
And if she says, "Phil,
the TV's driving me crazy,"
I should just say, "I know. There is not
enough quality programming for women."
No. Turn off the damn
TV. Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Okay, now I'm confused again.
- So I heard you had
a rough time today.
- Yeah, well...
Remember the days when
we thought we'd live forever?
Don't you wanna go
play? When do I ever play?
I'm kind of wrestling with this whole
older man, younger woman thing.
It's like Chloe and I grew
up in different worlds.
Today I made a joke about the
Wiggles. It went right over her head.
I don't know what that is. It's an
expression. It means she didn't get it.
Yeah, sometimes this age
thing knocks you in the head.
Is that what this is about?
I always knew your mother might remarry
after I'm gone. That never bothered me.
I figured her husbands
would be your dad, me...
and some putz who
could never live up to me.
But what if I'm
not the main guy?
What if some other guy
is? What if I'm the putz?
When my mom and
dad got divorced,
do you have any idea how
many guys chased after her?
The phone didn't stop ringing.
Men would stop
her on the street.
Guys would propose
to her from moving cars.
And they were good-looking
guys, Jay, with money.
I think one of them was a Kennedy.
Where are you going with this?
When you showed up, I
didn't think you had a prayer.
You were so nervous and
sweaty, I felt sorry for you.
I had to climb
three flights of stairs.
- But of all people,
my mom fell for you.
- I've got a few moves.
She said she fell in love
with you during your first fight.
What? She said she'd
finally met her match.
Huh.
So if you think she's just gonna
replace you when you're gone,
then you are the putz.
Thanks, kid. I appreciate that.
I thought you liked me when
I first showed up. Please.
For the first month, I didn't
even bother to learn your name.
Is she back yet?
She's on her way.
Did you find it? I did...
at the fifth store I went to.
It was in the window, and I had to undress
a mannequin while a creepy guy filmed it,
so we have that to look
forward to on the Internet.
Thank you so much,
Mom. You're welcome.
Now go put that exactly where
you found the other one, okay?
Okay. Mwah.
Uh-oh.
What? The security
tag, it's still on.
I told those people
to take that off.
Oh, no. She's pulling
into the driveway!
Okay, it's fine. It's fine.
Don't panic. I've got it.
She's getting out of
the car! I am doing it.
- I've almost got it. Oh, God.
- Oh, no.
- What is that?
- Well, it's ink.
Hide it.
She's in the house!
What are you doing with my
sweater? Oh, my God! It's ruined!
- It was an accident.
- I knew this would happen. You idiot!
Hey, hey. Let's
try to get along.
I wish she was never even born.
They were trying to
make one with a brain.
Ah! Ah!
Honey, you guys are
both... pretty smart.
Ah. Sheesh.
It's that sweater, huh?
Yeah, it is that sweater.
And I did everything I can
to stop them from fighting.
I don't understand why they
can't see how much you love them.
I don't know. Meanwhile, Cheryl
has been calling me all day...
because she's
angry I didn't show up.
Doesn't Cheryl have a housekeeper and a
nanny? Why does she need so much help?
I know, right?
You work so hard.
You do so much.
I do.
Of course you do. I do.
Oh, sweetie, thank you.
I really appreciate that.
Hey. Yeah?
Who's my gal?
I am. Darn right.
Yeah.
Let me get this.
Hey, by the way, do you notice
anything different about me?
Uh-uh.
Huh.
Hmm. What is it?
Nothing.
A haircut. A week ago.
Okay, so tell me.
Forget it. It's not important.
Okay. I'll just go start dinner.
Listen, I've been thinking.
When I go, I want you to know...
it's okay if you
marry someone else.
I know.
Because I want you to
be happy. I'll be happy.
You're driving me
crazy on purpose, right?
Jay, I'm not going
to marry anyone else.
That's what you say now. But no
one knows what the future holds.
So I want you to have this.
Ay, look at this.
An empty coffee can.
Do you know what
men used to buy me?
When I go, toss me in the fire,
sweep up my ashes,
stick 'em in that.
Ta-da!
We need to talk
about this "ta-da."
'Cause I don't care if it's in
a wall or if it's in the ground,
just as long as I
end up with you.
Aw, Jay.
It's perfect. Jay Pritchett
sitting on the mantel...
in the old coffee can.
That will drive the putz
crazy, and I like that.
Hey.
Um, so for whatever it's worth,
I called the adoption
attorney... adoption, yay...
And on Monday they're
gonna start the process...
of changing Lily's last
name to Tucker-Pritchett.
Great.
Again, I'm... I'm so sorry.
Okay.
Um... Oh, I, uh...
I took a quick pass at "Two
Monkeys and a Panda."
So just let me
know what you think.
"Once upon a time
there were two monkeys.
They loved each other very much,
but there was something missing."
A hyphen?
"They wanted a baby.
And they heard that there was a
very special baby in a faraway land...
who needed a family.
She was a panda named Lily.
One of the monkeys was scared.
They'd never had a panda before.
But they held
Lily in their arms,
and the scared monkey
became the brave one.
And the two monkeys"...
Coco and Miko.
- I'm sorry. What?
- Coco and Miko are
the names of the monkeys.
Really? That doesn't
seem like it's a little...
Coco and Miko. I
like that. I like that.
Coco and Miko. Yeah.
"They traveled all the way home with
the perfect panda that they adopted."
Did she just clap? She
heard "adopted" and clapped.
Cam, that's amazing.
Oh, my God. You did that.
Wha... You did
that. That is amazing.
I can't believe that.
And just like that, peace
returned to our house.
Well, technically,
it's my house, but...
I-I will... I will fix that too.
Once we finished writing the
book, we realized something.
We're not the only two
monkeys with a panda.
Gay parents are a huge market,
and no one's writing for them.
We thought we were
sitting on a gold mine.
But we weren't.
Let's see. Oh.
"Gay Parenting." Oh.
"Gay Adoptive Parenting." Okay.
"Gay Adoption
Foreign Children." Wow.
"Gay Adoption Asian
Children." What?
"Bisexual Adoption
Asian Children." Oh!
"Transgendered Adoption."
Okay, come on. Let's go, Miko.
English - US - Line 21